#### Contact

336-707-6499 (Mobile) nshertlein@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ nancyshertlein1953 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Emergency Nursing Cruise Ship Nursing Hospitals

#### Certifications

Occupational Health Practice Management

# Nancy Hertlein

Interim CNO at Alleghany Health

Greensboro, North Carolina

## Summary

Extensive leadership experience, a strong clinical background, and an excellent ability to collaborate with others to reach a common goal. Special strengths include problem identification and solving skills, successful multitasking capabilities, and the ability to communicate effectively. Certified in Emergency Nursing.

Nshertlein@hotmail.com 336-707-6499

## Experience

Alleghany Health Interim CNO October 2018 - Present (1 year 10 months) Sparta , NC

Ozarks Medical Center Interim Director Emergency Services September 2017 - April 2018 (8 months) West Plains, MO

Royal Caribbean Cruises Ltd.

Manager CareTeam and Strategic Development

March 2015 - July 2017 (2 years 5 months)

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

#### Cone Health

11 years

Director Moses Cone Urgent Care Center 2003 - 2014 (11 years) Greensboro, NC

Managed human, fiscal, and material resources at the Urgent Care Center for this six hospital health system, Responsible for design, delivery, and marketing of high quality services for this 35,000 visit per year, high acuity facility

Page 1 of 3

- Decreased time in department by 31 minutes through changes in flow, staffing patterns, and establishment of metrics for all employees.
- Led department staffing mix changes which resulted in savings of \$450K// year
- Implemented physician order entry in EMSTAT (Allscripts); complete implementation of ASAP emergency services program of EPIC ER
- Consistently exceeded point of care collection goals set by Cone Health Revenue Cycle Management

Director Employer Health Services
July 2011 - September 2013 (2 years 3 months)
Greensboro, NC

Led the successful merging of Employee Health and Occupational Health Services which serves approximately 10,000 Cone Health employees as well as over 500 external clients.

Assistant Director - Wesly Long Community Hospital September 2003 - December 2005 (2 years 4 months)

Assistant Director for Emergency Department serving approximately 45,000 patients per year.

- Patient satisfaction score moved to top decile from single digits
- Consistent improvement in all metric measured (door to triage; door to bed; door to MD)
- Implemented track scheduling and staggered shifts to better meet patient needs
- Utilized FISH Model to successfully improve teamwork and staff morale.

Norwegian Cruise Line Chief Nurse; Ship's Nurse Senior January 1983 - March 2003 (20 years 3 months)

Served on all ships in the NCL fleet, Worked in corporate office and onsite for new ship constructions. Established and updated medical department policies and procedures. Created a standard item lists for medications, supplies, and equipment. Managed all shipboard medical department employees.

## Education

University of North Carolina at Greensboro

BSN, Nursing

Pfeiffer University
MHA/MBA, Health Administration / Business Administration